<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>astrophotography on walking in the woods</title><link>http://chang48.github.io/categories/astrophotography/</link><description>Recent content in astrophotography on walking in the woods</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:06:54 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chang48.github.io/categories/astrophotography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Soul Nebula</title><link>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/11-24-soul-nebula/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:06:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/11-24-soul-nebula/</guid><description>&lt;p>Westerhout 5, or known by most as Soul Nebula, is an emission nebula located in Cassiopeia.
This is a large star forming region like the Orion Nebula. The dark hollow areas embedded
in the blue regions are cavities that were carved out by radiation and winds from the region&amp;rsquo;s
massive stars.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Veil Nebula</title><link>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/11-04-veil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 22:06:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/11-04-veil/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Veil Nebula. This is a 2x3 Mosaic narrow-band imaging project that took me almost two months (9/4/2022 ~ 11/1/2022)
to complete. A total of 2155 subs with 179 hours of accumulated exposure time. This nebula is a magnificent supernova
remnant in the area of Cygnus, one of my favorite constellations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Squid Nebula</title><link>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/07-04-squid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 15:16:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/07-04-squid/</guid><description>&lt;p>SH2-129 Flying Bat (red) and OU-4 Squid Nebulae. The combo can be found in the constellation Cepheus.
Both are in the family of emission nebula. The Flying Bat consists of mostly ionized hydrogen gas while
the Squid is a region full of ionized oxygen clouds. Due to its extremely dimness, the Squid was
discovered only recently in 2011 by French astrophotographer Nicolas Outters. The formation of
the Squid is still under debate. But many astronomers believe the bright star HD202214 (near the center
of the photo) plays a major role.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Horsehead Nebula</title><link>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/02-28-horsehead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:16:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://chang48.github.io/post/2022/02-28-horsehead/</guid><description>&lt;p>IC434 Horsehead Nebula. This nebula is probably one of the most imaged subject in astrophotography.
IC434 is a dark nebula in the constellation Orion. It is about 1375 light years away from Earth.
The nebula got its name because the dark dust cloud looks just like a horse&amp;rsquo;s head. Behind the
Horsehead nebula is a huge area of ionized hydrogen gas lit up by the star group Sigma Orions
(at the top of the image)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Orion Nebula</title><link>http://chang48.github.io/post/2021/11-05-orion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 12:30:04 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://chang48.github.io/post/2021/11-05-orion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Revisited the Orion Nebula M42. This time with the mighty (comparing to to WO Z61 MK2) Takahashi TSA-120N.
M42 is a very bright nebula so it is fairly straightforward to image overall. The most tricky part is probably
the Trapezium region where care must be taken in order to prevent overexposure. I managed to get a few hours
of LRGB data before the clouds kicked in. Applied a PixInsight HDR trick I learned from the internet to
process the Trapezium cluster region.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>